Register of the China Defense Supplies Records
Hoover Institution Archives
China Defense Supplies records
1940-1947
China Defense Supplies.
2008C96
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
50 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes, 1 oversize folder (23.1 linear feet)
The collection contains correspondence, memoranda, reports, and financial and personnel records relating to procurement and shipment of war materiel from the United States to China during World War II, military operations in the China-Burma-India Theater, and wartime diplomatic relations between China and the United States. The office files of William S. Youngman, Jr., President of China Defense Supplies, can be found throughout the collection.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into 8 series: General office file, Departments file, Transportation fuel executive file, American Volunteer Group (AVG)/Central Air Manufacturing Company (CAMCO) file, Chinese National Aviation Corporation (CNAC) file, Speeches and writings, Subject file, and Oversize materials.
Most folder headings are original
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2008, with an addition in 2011.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Materials
William Sterling Youngman papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Claire Lee Chennault papers, Hoover Institution Archives
T. V. (Tzu-wen) Soong papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Whiting Willauer papers, Princeton University Library Mudd Manuscripts Library
Historical Note
China Defense Supplies, Inc. was the main agency for coordinating Lend-Lease aid to China from the United States. Incorporated in the United States in 1941, China Defense Supplies was an organization of the Chinese government chaired by T. V. Soong, but staffed by Americans and based in Washington, D.C.
In 1941, China Defense Supplies worked to improve transportation over the Burma Road, the main Lend-Lease supply route to China. When the Japanese invasion of Burma in 1942 impeded access to the Burma Road, China Defense Supplies initiated the Emergency Air Transport Program to fly goods from India to China and helped to develop an air transport route over a stretch of the Himalayas nicknamed "The Hump." China Defense Supplies also worked to secure supplies for the American Volunteer Group, also known as the Flying Tigers.
As Soong spent increasingly less time in Washington during the latter years of the war, the decision was made to dissolve China Defense Supplies in 1944 and establish a successor organization, the Chinese Supply Commission, which was also active in obtaining reconstruction aid for China following the war. S. C. Wang became the chairman of this organization in September 1945, when the activities of the Chinese Supply Commission shifted from wartime supply to the procurement of materials needed to rebuild China's economy.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection contains correspondence, memoranda, reports, and financial and personnel records relating to procurement and shipment of war materiel from the United States to China during World War II, military operations in the China-Burma-India Theater, and wartime diplomatic relations between China and the United States. The office files of William S. Youngman, Jr., President of China Defense Supplies, can be found throughout the collection.
The General office file contains administrative documents such as financial and personnel records, in addition to correspondence and files on individuals employed by or associated with China Defense Supplies. This series includes a history of China Defense Supplies that provides detailed information about its various projects and discusses strategy decisions in the China-Burma-India Theater. Also included are daily reports, weekly information letters, and meeting minutes of the Planning Committee, which give an in-depth look at the activities of China Defense Supplies. On July 1, 1944, the Chinese Supply Commission was established as a successor organization to China Defense Supplies. Material created by the Chinese Supply Commission can be found within the general office file, in the correspondence, and scattered throughout the collection; these materials can be identified by date. Material organized by the activities of various departments of China Defense Supplies can be found in the Departments file, which is divided into six departments: Aviation, Medical and Miscellaneous Supplies, Motor Transport/Transportation, Ordnance, Signal Corps, and Traffic. For more material concerning the Motor Transport/Transportation Department, see the Oversize materials.
The Subject file contains information on projects that were central to the work of China Defense Supplies, such as Lend-Lease operations and supply routes. Included are documents on the Emergency Air Transport Program and the Burma Road. The reports by Gordon Tweedy and Don F. Harding (Box:42, folders 17-18 and Box:43, folders 1-3), mostly in the form of correspondence, discuss matters of interest in India. Materials created by various China Defense Supplies departments may also be found in this file.
The Transportation fuel executive file documents projects involving the Kansu Oil Fields and other fuel operations. Since fuel was integral to the work of both the Motor Transport/Transportation Department and the Aviation Department, materials relevant to those departments can be found in this file.
In addition to William Sterling Youngman's role as the president of China Defense Supplies, Youngman, who throughout the 1940s worked as an attorney in a firm headed by Thomas G. ("Tommy the Cork") Corcoran, also played a significant role in the American Volunteer Group (AVG). The American Volunteer Group, better known as the Flying Tigers, was a group that China Defense Supplies worked with to transport aid to the Chinese government prior to the U.S. entry into World War II. The pilots of the American Volunteer Group were paid through contracts with the Central Air Manufacturing Company (CAMCO), which also recruited pilots and acted as an intermediary between the Chinese government and the American Volunteer Group. The American Volunteer Group (AVG)/Central Air Manufacturing Company (CAMCO) file documents the financial relationship between CAMCO, the American Volunteer Group and China Defense Supplies. Materials include audits, financial documents, personnel files, and a roster of American Volunteer Group pilots. The general files consist mainly of correspondence, including letters from Claire Chennault and T. V. Soong.
When the American Volunteer Group disbanded in July 1942, some of its members joined the Chinese National Aviation Corporation (CNAC). Pilots from the Chinese National Aviation Corporation transported Lend-Lease supplies from India to China over a treacherous stretch of the Himalayan Mountains known as "The Hump." This series contains telegrams between Harold M. Bixby, Vice President of Pan American Airways, and William L. Bond, who was employed by CNAC. Since the Aviation Department of China Defense Supplies was involved in the work of both of these groups, materials on the American Volunteer Group and the Chinese National Aviation Corporation can be found in the Departments file under the Aviation Department subseries and under air transport in the Subject file.
The Speeches and writings series contains drafts of speeches by T. V. Soong, who served as chairman of China Defense Supplies. His correspondence can be found throughout the collection.
Youngman, William Sterling, 1907-1994.; China--Foreign relations--United States.; Lend-lease operations (1941-1945); United States--Foreign relations--China.; World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns--Burma.; World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns--China.; World War, 1939-1945--China.; World War, 1939-1945--Diplomatic history.; World War, 1939-1945--Equipment and supplies.; World War, 1939-1945--Transportation.; World War, 1939-1945--United States.
- General office file, 1940-1947 (Box 1-13)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes correspondence, memoranda, financial documents, personnel files, and reports. Arranged alphabetically by subject or format.
  - General, 1942-1945 (Folder 1: 1)
  - Activities of China Defense Supplies, 1941-1944 (Folder 1: 2)
  - Addresses, 1942-1943, 1946 (Folder 1: 3-4)
  - Administrative, 1941-1943 (Folder 1: 5)
  - Air priority (Folder 1)
    - Certificates, 1942-1943 (Folder 1: 6-8)
    - Correspondence, 1943-1944 (Folder 1: 9)
    - Domestic, 1943-1944 (Folder 1: 10)
    - Foreign travel, 1942-1943 (Folder 1: 11)
  - Audits, 1941-1944 (Folder 1: 12)
  - Balance sheet, 1941 (Folder 2: 1)
  - Bank notes, 1942 (Folder 2: 2-3)
  - Bank of China, 1941-1942 (Folder 2: 4)
  - Board of Directors (Folder 2)
    - Agenda for first meeting, 1941 (Folder 2: 5)
    - Annual meeting, circa 1945 (Folder 2: 6)
    - Meetings, 1941-1943 (Folder 2: 7)
  - By-laws, undated (Folder 2: 8)
  - By-laws and certificate of incorporation, 1941, undated (Folder 2: 9)
  - Chinese Supply Commission (Folder 2)
    - Administrative, 1945-1946 (Folder 2: 10)
    - Advisers, 1946-1947 (Folder 2: 11)
      From the files of John B. Nason
    - Letter from Youngman about formation of the Chinese Supply Commission and other materials, 1943-1945 (Folder 2: 12)
    - Reports (Folder 2)
      - General Situation Report on CSC Affairs, 1947 (Folder 2: 13)
      - Report on Lend-Lease operations, May 7, 1945 (Folder 2: 14)
      - "Report on the Work of the Chinese Supply Commission, September 1945-February 1947" (Folder 2: 15)
      - Reports to China, 1946-1947 (Folder 2: 16)
      - "Summary of Chinese Supply Commission Operations During 1946,", 1947 (Folder 2: 17)
  - Complaint file, 1942 (Folder 2: 18)
    Includes memos for the president and letters to Hopkins and Stimson
  - Contracts, 1941 (Folder 2: 19)
  - Coordination of liaison activities, 1941 (Folder 2: 20)
  - Correspondence (Folder 2)
    - Letters (Folder 2)
      - General (Folder 2)
        - 1941 (Folder 2: 21)
        - 1942 (Folder 2: 22)
        - 1943 (Folder 3: 1)
        - 1944 (Folder 3: 2)
        - 1945 (Folder 3: 3)
      - Chen, R.C., 1941-1943 (Folder 3: 4)
      - China Defense Supplies offices in the Far East, 1943-1944 (Folder 3: 5)
      - Courtesy letters, incoming, 1942 (Folder 3: 6)
      - Export applications, 1941-1942 (Folder 3: 7)
      - Liaison correspondence, 1941-1942 (Folder 3: 8)
      - Miscellaneous, 1941-1942 (Folder 3: 9)
    - Telegrams (Folder 3)
      - General (Folder 3)
        - 1941 (Folder 3: 10-11)
        - 1942 (Folder 3: 12-15)
        - 1943 (Folder 3: 16)
        - 1943 (Folder 4: 1)
        - 1944 (Folder 4: 2-3)
        - 1946. (Folder 4: 4-9)
          Includes materials from the files of John B. Nason and William S. Youngman
        - 1947. (Folder 4: 10-13)
      - Air shipments, 1942-1944 (Folder 4: 14)
      - Boat shipments, 1943-1944 (Folder 5: 1-2)
      - Chen, R.C., 1941-1942 (Folder 5: 3-5)
      - Chiang, Kai-Shek, 1942 (Folder 5: 6)
      - Drafts, 1942, undated (Folder 5: 7)
      - London (Wellington Koo), 1941-1942 (Folder 5: 8)
      - Shaughnessy, M. Quinn, 1942 (Folder 6: 1-2)
      - Tweedy, Gordon, 1942 (Folder 6: 3-4)
  - Department indexes, 1942 (Folder 6: 5)
  - Duties of personnel on payroll, 1944 (Folder 6: 6)
  - Executive file, 1941 (Folder 6: 7)
  - Expense account of John B. Nason, 1941-1944 (Folder 6: 8)
  - Expenses and salaries, 1943 (Folder 6: 9)
  - Finance Committee, 1942-1944 (Folder 6: 10-11)
  - Finances, 1942-1944 (Folder 6: 12)
  - Financial reports, 1942-1945 (Folder 6: 13-14)
  - Foreign funds control, forms, and correspondence, 1941 (Folder 7: 1)
  - Guard force, 1942-1944 (Folder 7: 2)
  - Guard schedules, 1942-1943, undated (Folder 7: 3)
  - History of China Defense Supplies (Folder 7)
    - Appendices to January 17, 1944 report and notes, 1943-1944 (Folder 7: 4)
    - Correspondence, 1944 (Folder 7: 5)
    - Final report, 1945 (Folder 7: 6-7)
    - "A Short History of China Defense Supplies, Inc.", 1942 (Folder 7: 8)
    - Working papers, 1944-1945 (Folder 7: 9)
  - Holiday, 1943 (Folder 7: 10)
  - Individuals (Folder 7-8)
    - Alsop, Joseph Wright, Jr. (Folder 7)
      - General, 1943, undated (Folder 7: 11)
      - Receipts, 1941 (Folder 7: 12)
    - Blandford, John, Jr., 1946 (Folder 7: 13)
    - Bond, W. L., 1941-1942 (Folder 7: 14)
    - Bonnevale, R. W., 1941-1942 (Folder 7: 15)
    - Brennan, James J., 1942-1945 (Folder 8: 1)
    - Corcoran, David M., 1942 (Folder 8: 2)
    - Currie, Lauchlin, 1941-1942 (Folder 8: 3)
    - Davies, John, 1942 (Folder 8: 4)
    - Elder, James C., 1942 (Folder 8: 5)
    - Eliot, George Fielding (Indian Ocean), 1942 (Folder 8: 6)
    - Fraumann, George B., 1942-1944 (Folder 8: 7)
    - Gullander, Elsa, 1942 (Folder 8: 8)
    - Harding, Donald F. (Folder 8)
      - General, 1942-1944 (Folder 8: 9)
      - Selective Service file, 1942-1944 (Folder 8: 10)
    - Ho, Hanson, 1942 (Folder 8: 11)
    - Hopkins, Harry, 1942 (Folder 8: 12)
    - Li, E. C., 1942 (Folder 8: 13)
    - Lloyd, Madison E., 1942-1943 (Folder 8: 14)
    - Lovett, Robert, 1941-1942 (Folder 8: 15)
    - Lui, J. Heng, 1941-1942 (Folder 8: 16)
    - Matteson, E. L., 1942 (Folder 8: 17)
    - Morris, Lawrence, 1941-1942 (Folder 8: 18)
    - Nason, John B., 1943-1944 (Folder 8: 19)
    - Price, Frank W., 1941 (Folder 8: 20)
    - Price, Harry B. (Folder 8)
      - General, 1941-1944 (Folder 8: 21-23)
      - Correspondence on articles, 1942 (Folder 8: 24)
    - Ostrow, Arnold, 1941-1942 (Folder 8: 25)
    - Rajchman, Ludwick (Folder 8)
      - General, 1941-1943 (Folder 8: 26)
        Includes Rajchman's statement on the transition period
      - Health projects, 1941 (Folder 8: 27)
        Includes malaria mission
    - Ray, Frank, 1942-1943 (Folder 8: 28)
    - Schaberg, Benjamin F., 1942 (Folder 8: 29)
    - Shaughnessy, M. Quinn, 1941-1944 (Folder 8: 30)
    - Shen, T. H., 1942-1943 (Folder 8: 31)
    - Soong, T. V. (Trip to Chungking), 1942 (Folder 8: 32)
    - Taub, Alex, 1945-1946 (Folder 8: 33)
    - Tweedy, Gordon, 1942-1945 (Folder 9: 1)
    - Willauer, Whiting (Folder 9)
      - General, 1942-1944 (Folder 9: 2)
      - Trip to China, 1942-1944 (Folder 9: 3)
    - Williams, Donald H., 1944 (Folder 9: 4)
  - Insurance, C.C. Chien of National Resources Commission, 1945, undated (Folder 9: 5)
  - Insurance, maritime, 1942-1944 (Folder 9: 6)
  - Interoffice, miscellaneous, 1842-1943 (Folder 9: 7)
  - Library list, 1942-1943 (Folder 9: 8)
  - Liquidation of China Defense Supplies (Folder 9)
    - Correspondence with T. V. Soong, 1944-1945 (Folder 9: 9)
    - Property in Washington, 1944-1947 (Folder 9: 10)
    - Telegrams to T. V. Soong, 1944-1945 (Folder 9: 11)
  - Long distance telephone calls, undated (Folder 9: 12)
  - Mail distribution, 1941-1943 (Folder 9: 13)
  - Mailing list (War Agencies - United China Relief), 1942 (Folder 9: 14)
  - Meeting minutes (Folder 9-10)
    - Executive Committee, 1943-1945 (Folder 9: 15)
    - Staff and executive meetings, 1942-1943 (Folder 9: 16-18)
    - Staff and executive meetings, 1943-1944 (Folder 10: 1-2)
    - War Department, organization, 1941 (Folder 10: 3)
  - Memoranda, 1941-1947 (Folder 10: 4-6)
  - Memoranda to all China Defense Supplies staff, 1942-1943 (Folder 10: 7)
  - Office schedule, 1942, undated (Folder 10: 8)
  - Offices (Folder 10)
    - 1212 18th Street, Northwest, 1942 (Folder 10: 9)
    - 1601 V Street, Northwest, 1942-1943 (Folder 10: 10)
    - 2020 16th Street, Northwest, 1942 (Folder 10: 11)
    - 2110 LeRoy Place, Aviation Department, 1943 (Folder 10: 12)
    - 2311 Massachusetts Avenue, Northwest, 1942-1943 (Folder 10: 13-14)
    - Maintenance, 1942 (Folder 10: 15)
  - Organization and liaison relations, 1942 (Folder 10: 16)
  - Organization in China, 1941-1942 (Folder 10: 17)
  - Passport information, 1942 (Folder 10: 18)
  - Payroll, 1942, undated (Folder 10: 19)
  - Payroll working sheets, 1942-1942 (Folder 10: 20)
  - Personnel (Folder 10-11)
    - General, 1941-1944 (Folder 10: 21-22)
    - Applicants, 1942-1943 (Folder 11: 1)
    - Checks and salary information, 1941-1946 (Folder 11: 2)
    - Lists, 1942-1943, undated (Folder 11: 3)
    - Local staff, 1941 (Folder 11: 4)
    - Officers and staff members, salaries, 1942-1943 (Folder 11: 5)
    - Organization by department, 1941-1943 (Folder 11: 6)
    - Reports to Justice Department, 1942-1946 (Folder 11: 7)
  - Planning Committee, 1942-1944 (Folder 11: 8-11)
  - Priority Board (Folder 11)
    - General, 1942 (Folder 11: 12)
    - Meetings, 1942 (Folder 11: 13)
  - Records and Reports Department, 1941-1942 (Folder 11: 14)
  - Reports (Folder 11-12)
    - Daily reports (Folder 11-12)
      - 1941 (Folder 11: 15)
      - 1941 (Folder 12: 1)
      - 1942 (Folder 12: 2)
    - Reports to T. V. Soong, 1940-1942 (Folder 12: 3)
    - Weekly information letters, 1943-1944 (Folder 12: 4-5)
    - Weekly reports, 1942-1943 (Folder 12: 6)
  - Requests for travel authorization, 1941-1942 (Folder 12: 7)
  - Riggs National Bank, special account, Corcoran, Bonnevalle, Morris, 1941 (Folder 12: 8)
  - Salaries Committee, 1942-1944 (Folder 12: 9-11)
  - Selective Service data, 1943-1944 (Folder 13: 1)
  - Special policemen, 1942-1943 (Folder 13: 2)
  - State Department forms (Folder 13)
    - PR-1, foreign official status notification, 1941-1943 (Folder 13: 3)
      Includes employment applications
    - PR-2, 1941-1944 (Folder 13: 4)
  - Taxes (Folder 13)
    - General, 1941-1944 (Folder 13: 5)
    - D.C. taxes, 1944-1945, undated (Folder 13: 6)
  - Unemployment Compensation Board, 1944 (Folder 13: 7)
  - Visit requests, 1942 (Folder 13: 8)
  - War Department, badges, 1943-1944 (Folder 13: 9)
  - Miscellany, 1943-1944 (Folder 13: 10)
- Departments file, 1940-1944 (Box 13-25)
  Includes correspondence, memoranda, supply lists, and reports. Arranged into 6 groups by department, then alphabetically by subject or format.
  - Aviation Department
    - General, 1941-1942 (Folder 13: 11-12)
    - General, 1942-1944 (Folder 14: 1-6)
    - Air equipment, 1944 (Folder 14: 7)
    - Air fields, 1943 (Folder 14: 8)
    - Airplane allocations, 1942-1943 (Folder 14: 9)
    - Air shipments from the U.S., 1942 (Folder 14: 10)
    - Air Transportation Committee, 1943-1944 (Folder 14: 11-13)
    - Allocations and assignments, 1942 (Folder 14: 14)
    - Ammunition, 1941-1944 (Folder 14: 15)
    - Aviation advisor, 1941 (Folder 14: 16)
    - Aviation requirements, undated (Folder 14: 17)
    - Cargo planning data, 1942-1943, undated. (Folder 14: 18)
      Includes blueprints
    - Cargo planning data, 1942-1943 (Folder 15: 1)
    - China's requirements for planes, 1941-1944 (Folder 15: 2)
    - Chinese government plans for planes, 1942 (Folder 15: 3)
    - Chinese training program, 1941-1942 (Folder 15: 4)
    - Correspondence (Folder 15)
      - General, 1941-1943 (Folder 15: 5)
      - Sinclair, 1942 (Folder 15: 6)
    - Conditions of India-China route, 1942, undated (Folder 15: 7)
    - Deliveries and diversions of cargo planes, 1942, undated (Folder 15: 8)
    - Equipment list of First Ferrying Group, undated (Folder 15: 9)
    - Flight summaries, 1943-1944 (Folder 15: 10)
    - Fuel tanks, 1942 (Folder 15: 11)
    - Gasoline containers, 1942 (Folder 15: 12)
      See also Transportation fuel executive file and Departments file -Motor Transport/Transportation Department
    - Gliders, 1940-1942 (Folder 15: 13)
    - India-China-Burma transport, 1942-1943 (Folder 15: 14)
    - Lend-Lease budgets, 1942 (Folder 15: 15)
    - Lend-Lease technicians sent to Far East, 1942 (Folder 15: 16)
    - Link trailers, 1942 (Folder 15: 17)
    - Meteorological equipment, 1941-1942 (Folder 16: 1)
    - Nitrate dope, lacquer and thinner, 1943 (Folder 16: 2)
    - Planes (Folder 16)
      - C-47 test flight, 1942 (Folder 16: 3)
      - C-47 transports, 1942-1944 (Folder 16: 4)
      - C-53 transports, 1942 (Folder 16: 5)
      - C-54 transports, 1944, undated (Folder 16: 6)
      - C-60 transports, 1942 (Folder 16: 7)
      - P-40, 1941 (Folder 16: 8)
    - Photographic equipment, 1942 (Folder 16: 9)
    - Procedure for procurement and shipment, 1942-1943 (Folder 16: 10)
    - Requirements, 1941-1943 (Folder 16: 11)
    - Requisitions, 1941 (Folder 16: 12)
    - Searchlights and sound locators, 1941-1942 (Folder 16: 13)
    - Set up of Aviation Department with War Department, 1942-1943 (Folder 16: 14)
    - Shipping tonnage requirements, 1942 (Folder 16: 15)
    - Spare parts and repairing materials, 1941-1944 (Folder 16: 16)
    - Status reports, 1942 (Folder 16: 17)
    - Teletypes, 1942-1943 (Folder 16: 18)
    - Two-speed engines (Folder 16)
      - Correspondence, 1942-1943 (Folder 16: 19)
      - Reports and test flight records, 1943 (Folder 16: 20)
    - Universal Trading Corporation, purchases and orders, 1941 (Folder 16: 21)
    - Weekly Newark inventory reports, 1942-1943 (Folder 16: 22)
    - "What Airplanes Can Do," by Edward Warner, 1942 (Folder 16: 23)
    - Wooden cargo aircraft, 1942 (Folder 16: 24)
  - Medical and Miscellaneous Supplies Department
    - American Bureau for Medical Aid to China, 1942 (Folder 17: 1)
    - Chinese Government War Supplies Agency, 1944 (Folder 17: 2)
    - Correspondence, 1942-1943 (Folder 17: 3)
    - Dehydrated foods, 1942-1943 (Folder 17: 4)
    - Food concentrates, 1942-1943 (Folder 17: 5)
    - General supplies, 1941 (Folder 17: 6)
    - Inventory, 1942-1943 (Folder 17: 7)
    - Inventory of supplies in India, undated (Folder 17: 8)
    - Medical, 1941-1943, undated (Folder 17: 9)
    - Medical Relief Corps (Robert Lim's report), 1941 (Folder 17: 10)
    - Medical supplies, 1941-1942 (Folder 17: 11-12)
    - Miscellaneous supplies, 1941 (Folder 17: 13)
    - Personal equipment, 1941-1942 (Folder 17: 14)
    - Procedure for procurement, 1942-1943 (Folder 17: 15)
    - Red Cross (Folder 17)
      - General, 1941-1943 (Folder 17: 16)
      - Conference, 1941 (Folder 17: 17)
      - Statistics, Chinese receipts and needs, 1941-1942 (Folder 17: 18)
    - Requests for assignment, 1943 (Folder 17: 19)
    - Requirements, 1941, undated (Folder 17: 20)
    - Requirements for 1943 programs, 1942 (Folder 17: 21)
    - Requirements for 1944 programs, 1943-1944 (Folder 18: 1)
    - Requirements for 1945 programs, 1943-1944 (Folder 18: 2)
    - Requirements for Northwest Epizootic Bureau of the Ministry of Agriculture, 1944 (Folder 18: 3)
    - Requirements from India and China, 1942-1943. (Folder 18: 4)
      Includes National Health Administration requirements
    - Status report of miscellaneous supplies, 1944 (Folder 18: 5)
  - Motor Transport/Transportation Department
    - General, 1941-1944, undated (Folder 18: 6-9)
    - Asphalt, 1941 (Folder 18: 10)
    - Boats and barges, 1942-1943 (Folder 18: 11)
    - Correspondence, 1941 (Folder 19: 1)
    - Diesel engines, 1943 (Folder 19: 2)
    - Fuel - Vegetable oils for motor fuel, 1942-1943 (Folder 19: 3)
    - Gasogenes, 1943 (Folder 19: 4)
    - Gasoline containers, 1942-1943. (Folder 19: 5)